(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-08T21:17:54.006310",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
青くて澄んだ空をぎゅっと抱きしめて
Holding the blue, clear sky tight in my arms,
今日も快晴だ
Today is clear weather too.
「知らない」はきっと怖くて
"Not knowing" is surely frightening,
「わかる」はきっと安心できる
And "knowing" surely brings peace of mind.
でも私が選ぶのは「ありえない」の向こう側
Yet what I choose is beyond the "impossible".
青くて澄んだ空を胸いっぱい吸い込んで
Breathing in the blue, clear sky deep into my chest,
透明になるまで 声を鳴らせ
Letting my voice ring out until I become transparent.
誰かの救いになったら
If I could become someone's salvation,
奇跡の一つでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could work even a single miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる
My singing voice melts into the morning,
悲しみごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
Embracing every sorrow, taking on a slight warmth.
そうだ、この気持ちに名を付けるなら
Yes, if I were to give this feeling a name—
熱いのはきっと端から冷めて
Heat surely cools from the edges,
定番になれば御の字さ
And becoming standard is good enough.
せっかくならみんなでさ 笑った顔見合っていこうぜ
If we're going all out, let's look at each other and smile together.
青くて瞬く夢を
A blue, twinkling dream—
胸いっぱいしまい込んで
Stowing it deep inside my chest,
熟れた分だけ思い出となれ
Letting it turn into memories as much as it has ripened.
私がただ幸せだったなら
If I were simply happy,
悔やむことさえなかったら
If there was nothing even to regret,
心に眠った衝動に気付くこともないから
I wouldn't even notice the impulse sleeping in my heart.
歌声は涙に寄り添う
My singing voice draws close to tears,
ときめきごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
Embracing every flutter of excitement, taking on a slight warmth.
そうだ、この気持ちに名を付けるなら
Yes, if I were to give this feeling a name—
花が咲けば枯れていく
Flowers bloom and then wither,
種を蒔けば宿っていく
Sow seeds and they take root.
運命に意味なんて元から無いんじゃない?
Wasn't there no meaning in fate to begin with?
咲き誇れ 散り笑え
Bloom proudly, scatter and smile.
私が誰かを照らせるなら
If I could shine a light on someone,
誰かの救いになったら
If I could become someone's salvation,
奇跡の一つでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could work even a single miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる
My singing voice melts into the morning,
悲しみごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
Embracing every sorrow, taking on a slight warmth.
空が温かくてきれいだ
The sky is warm and beautiful.
私はなんだか小粒な
Somehow, I feel like this tiny
この気持ちが愛おしくて大好きだったんだ
feeling is so precious and dear to me.
名前のないこの気持ちを
This nameless feeling—
解説 修正 早え こぜ マイストラテジー
Explanation, fix, so fast, my strategy!
君と共に行けるかな
Can we go together?
あっ 光った流れ星願いそびれ
Ah, a shooting star flashed, I missed my wish
もう一回を待った
and waited for another chance.
あっ という間に夜が明け
Ah, before I knew it, day broke,
もういいやこのまま散歩しよう
oh well, let's take a walk just like this.
あっ 横切ったノラネコ 色は黒?でも可愛いから優勝
Ah, a stray cat crossed by—black? But cute, so it wins!
パン屋さんがあくのは7時あと10分なににしようっかな 遠回り
The bakery opens at 7, 10 minutes left. What should I get? Let's take the long way.
もーしーもーしー 亀さんよ
Hello, hello, Mr. Turtle,
今だけは君になりたい
just for now, I want to be you.
ひょん って飛んだうさぎさん ひょんなこと 鼯がふる 豹に出会う
"Hyon," hopped the rabbit. By some odd chance, flying squirrels fall and I meet a leopard.
理屈だってないようなもので ファンタジー浮かべ今日もニヒルる
With things that make no reason, I float fantasies and act cynical again today.
その街灯すら意外と 僕がイヤホン外したら歌い出す
Even that streetlamp surprisingly starts singing when I take off my earphones.
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
The temperature of the voice that is only visible in winter—
春や夏や秋はどこへと消えてしまうのか
where do spring, summer, and autumn make it vanish to?
ききっとそこにある
Surely, it's right there.
触れる 揺らぐ 気づいて 気づいて って まるで心の中みたい
Touching, wavering, "notice me, notice me"—it's just like inside my heart.
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
The temperature of the voice that is only visible in winter—
春や夏や秋は誰かに届いているのかな だもとここにない
is it reaching someone in spring, summer, or autumn? Yet it's not here.
消える 消える 暑さも 寒さも 全部「ちょうどいい」の前詠え
Fading, fading, both the heat and cold. Sing before it's all "just right".
「わっ」 瞬間、風が吹いた どこかの桶屋が儲かったのだろう
"Wa!" In an instant, the wind blew. I wonder if some cooper profited from it.
彼女が大事に認めた特大サイズのラブレター
An extra-large love letter that she carefully wrote down
空を舞って、伝って、僕が拾う
dances through the sky, gets passed along, and I pick it up.
そんな運命待ちを途中下車 僕は自分の呼吸を重ねる
Getting off midway from waiting for such destiny, I layer my own breathing.
長い長い旅ゆっくりと進んでく 何でも解決してくれる「時間」ってやつが相棒だから
Advancing slowly on a long, long journey, because "time" that solves everything is my buddy.
息を吸って 長い長い旅おなかへった
Inhaling, I'm hungry on this long, long journey.
そろそろ…… 焼きたてのパンの香りに
Soon... attracted by the scent of freshly baked bread,
思わず、亀もうさぎに乗る 街灯も瞬いて眠った
instinctively, even the turtle rides the rabbit. The streetlamps also blinked and fell asleep.
入れ替わり目を覚ました 鳥たち もしもし 思考召し
Birds woke up taking turns. Hello, calling for thoughts,
どきどきは きせき 帽子召し はじまり はじまり
pounding hearts are miracles. Summoning hats, let the beginning begin,
おーしかし はじまり はじまり おーしかし 「おいしそ」
oh-shikashi, let it begin, oh-shikashi, "looks delicious."
ここはどこ 私は誰 とっけ？
Where is this, who am I again?
色とりどり よりどりみどり
Colorful, a rich variety of choices,
選択肢はたくさんあるけど
though there are so many options,
悩んでる時間がももり
the time spent worrying feels fleeting.
回転だシュートですとうだ
It's spin, shoot, and touchdown!
はいになっちゃって お互いになっちゃって 消費する 速度が
Becoming yes, becoming each other, the speed of consumption
息急いで走った分だけ 寿命だって早くきちゃったりして
makes it so that just by running out of breath, my lifespan might come to an end even faster.
息切れして 声も出ないの
I'm out of breath and can't even make a sound.
タイムパフォーマンス コストパフォーマンス 言葉踊り狂う僕らの背の上
Time performance, cost performance—words go wild dancing on our backs.
毎日焼かれてやり場ないよ ランチタイムくらいまったりさせて
Getting roasted every day with nowhere to go, at least let me relax during lunchtime.
ハートご奉仕かない
It's all heartfelt service.
さあ掘り込め 口の中が溶けていく
Now dig in as everything inside your mouth melts away.
あれここはどこ私は誰とっけ？
Wait, where is this, who am I again?
背景 石の上にも3年もいられない者たちへ
To those who can't stay even three years on a cold stone backdrop,
苛立っていい やめたっていい 両端店 還元大還元
it's okay to be frustrated, it's okay to quit. Storewide reduction, huge reduction!
デキ・イジ・ディフォ・コネ 感情乱打は思考のフェイス
Skill, tease, default, connections—emotional bashing is the face of thought.
頑張るって無駄のベイ 半身半霊
Trying hard is a useless bay, half-body, half-spirit.
色誇りより 風邪いもりもり
More than pride in colors, colds are piled high.
流れるの ゆるやかにめでて
Cherish the gentle flow of time,
味わい尽くそ 暇がままわれ
and savor it fully as leisure takes over.
してるはずが焦り耳を塞いで
Though I should be doing that, impatience makes me plug my ears.
どうになっちゃって ああ脳になっちゃって 魔もーする 心が
Becoming somehow, ah, becoming all brain, my guarding heart
そぎ落して 脂肪多分だけ やせ細って弱くなっちゃったりして
shaving off probably just fat, growing thin and weak.
息を吸って 声を出して
Inhale, let your voice out.
あれもしたい これもしたい そんな欲望を抱けるだけのあたしの人生
Wanting this, wanting that—just a life of mine capable of holding such desires.
愛そっとおりひらいて おとなっちゃって
Open up love gently and become an adult,
花咲じゅんべん なんてまっぴらまっぴら ごめんなさい
spring blooming routine is out of the question, no thank you.
タイムパフォーマンス コストパフォーマンス 言葉踊り狂う僕らの背の上
Time performance, cost performance—words go wild dancing on our backs.
毎日焼かれてやり場ないよ ランチタイムくらいまったりさせて
Getting roasted every day with nowhere to go, at least let me relax during lunchtime.
ハートご奉仕かない
It's all heartfelt service.
さあ掘り込め 口の中が溶けていく
Now dig in as everything inside your mouth melts away.
あれここはどこ私を探して
Wait, where is this, search for me.
青くて澄んだ空をぎゅっと抱きしめて
Clutching the blue, clear sky tight,
今日も快晴だ
today is clear skies too.
「知らない」はきっと怖くて
"Not knowing" is surely scary,
「わかる」はきっと安心できる
and "knowing" surely brings peace of mind.
でも私が選ぶのは「ありえない」の向こう側
Yet what I choose is beyond the impossible.
青くて澄んだ空を胸いっぱい吸い込んで
Inhaling the blue, clear sky deep into my chest,
透明になるまで声を鳴らせ
I'll make my voice ring out until it turns transparent.
私が誰かを照らせるなら 誰かの救いになったら
If I can illuminate someone, if I could be someone's salvation,
奇跡の一つでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could cause even a miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる
My singing voice melts and becomes morning,
悲しみごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
embracing the sadness and taking on a slight fever.
そうだ、この気持ちに名を付けるなら
That's right, if I were to name this feeling,
「アツい」はきっと端から冷めて
"Hotness" surely cools from the edges,
「定番」になれば御の字
and becoming a "classic" is a blessing.
せっかくならみんなでさ 笑い顔見せ合っていこうぜ
Since we're at it, let's show each other our smiling faces together.
青くて春な夢を胸いっぱい背負い込んで
Carrying a blue, spring-like dream fully on my chest,
熟れたその分だけ 思い出になれ
as much as it has ripened, may it become a memory.
私がただ幸せだったら 悔やむことさえなかったら
If I had just been happy, if there was nothing to regret,
心に眠った衝動に気付くこともないから
I wouldn't even notice the impulse sleeping in my heart.
歌声は涙に寄り添う
My singing voice draws close to tears,
ときめきごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
embracing the fluttering heart and taking on a slight fever.
そうだ、この気持ちに名を付けるなら
That's right, if I were to name this feeling,
花が咲けば枯れていく
Flowers bloom and then wither,
種を蒔けば宿っていく
seeds are sown and then take root.
運命に意味なんて元から無いんじゃない? 咲き誇れ 散り笑え
Wasn't there no meaning to destiny from the start? Bloom proudly, scatter and smile.
私が誰かを照らせるなら 誰かの救いになったら
If I can illuminate someone, if I could be someone's salvation,
奇跡の一つでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could cause even a miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる
My singing voice melts and becomes morning,
悲しみごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
embracing the sadness and taking on a slight fever.
空が温かくてきれいだ
The sky is warm and beautiful.
私はなんだか小粒な この気持ちが愛おしくて大好きだったんだ
I somehow found this tiny feeling so endearing and loved it so much.
名前のないこの気持ちを
This nameless feeling...
私が誰かを照らせるなら 誰かの救いになったら
If I can illuminate someone, if I could be someone's salvation,
奇跡の一つでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could cause even a miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる
My singing voice melts and becomes morning,
悲しみごと抱いて微熱を帯びる
embracing the sadness and taking on a slight fever.
綺麗な世界で生きていった そんなのズルいよな
Living in a beautiful world, isn't that unfair?
偽りを身に纏って 心のままカオティックに
Clad in falsehoods, remaining chaotic in my heart.
ああ、他人事みたいな夜だ
Ah, it's a night that feels like someone else's business.
ばらまいた星だけがキラリ澄んでいる
Only the scattered stars are glittering and clear.
そんなに綺麗にはなれないや
I can't become that pretty.
それでも今夜往くための歌
Even so, this is a song for going forth tonight.
ああ、ほんの小さな夜だ
Ah, it's a truly tiny night.
寝るには早く、夜明けはまだ遠く
Too early to sleep, dawn is still far off,
憧れるには遅く、挫けるにはまだ早い
too late to yearn, still too early to break down.
言葉はいつまでも下手だよ
Words are always clumsy,
ため息だけが上手になるよ
only sighs get better.
傷付く度、違う生き物だと知るよ
Every time I get hurt, I learn I'm a different creature.
それでも一杯歌うよ
Even so, I'll sing with all my heart.
泣きたい夜があったなら
If there was a night you wanted to cry,
笑えない夜があったなら
if there was a night you couldn't smile,
溶けて消えて無くなって きっともう一度ゼロから始めよう
melting, vanishing and disappearing—let's surely start over from zero once more.
明日のことはわからないや
I don't know about tomorrow,
昨日のことも知らないや
I don't know about yesterday either.
明けない夜があったって 私は煌めく星になれなくていい
Even if there's a night that never breaks, I don't need to become a glittering star.
煌めく星になれなくていい
I don't need to become a glittering star.
切なすぎた夜空だった
It was a night sky that was too painful...
儚すぎたでも
It was too fleeting, but...
きっと美しすぎて
surely it was too beautiful...
言葉は いつまでも下手だよ
My words are always so clumsy...
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only my sighs get better.
傷ついて 違う生き物だとしても
Even if we're hurt and different creatures,
それでも 精一杯歌うよ
still, I'll sing with all my might.
泣きたい夜があったなら
If there is a night you want to cry,
笑えない夜があったなら
if there is a night you cannot smile,
溶けて消えてなくなって
melting, fading away,
きっともう一度ゼロから始めよう
let's surely start over from zero once more.
明日のことは分からないや
I don't know anything about tomorrow,
昨日のことも知らないや
and I don't know anything about yesterday either.
明けない夜があったって
Even if there's a night that won't break into dawn,
私はきらめく星になれなくていい
I don't need to become a twinkling star.
きらめく星になれなくていい
I don't need to become a twinkling star—
そんな今夜 素敵に生きるための歌
a song to live wonderfully tonight.
窓の向こうを ほしたちを
Beyond the window, the stars...
数えてたら 眠ってた
as I counted them, I fell asleep.
その寝息を のいつか混ざる
That breathing... mixing someday
画面の向こう そばにいる
beyond the screen, being right by your side.
言葉なんてない
There are no words,
傷つくこともない
no getting hurt either,
まるでエトランゼ 愛しくで
just like an etranger, so dear...
こんなにそばにいるのに本当は遠い
Even though you're so close, you're actually far away.
伝えてた言葉が 涙になったプレイヤー
The words I tried to convey became tears, player.
今日もがんばったんだね
You worked hard again today, didn't you?
本当は手を差し伸べたい 私の知らない
I actually want to reach out my hand, to things I don't know—
キミのことを どうすればいい
what should I do about you?
どうすればいい なんてもない
What should I do? There's nothing like that,
何かすると 崩れそう
if I do something, it feels like it'll collapse.
ひとりここで 思いをはせ 時間だけが過ぎてゆく
Alone here, pondering as time just passes by.
知らない道 ほしは広がってて
An unknown road, stars spreading out.
君だけ、君だけを待ってる
Waiting only for you, only for you...
蜘蛛の巣を抜けよう
Breaking through the spider's web...
揺ら揺らと
Swaying, swaying...
いい道は 心地いいのにな
Even though a good path feels so nice...
いいのに
Even though it should be...
どんなにそばにいるのに 本当は遠い存在
Even though you're right beside me, you're actually so far away.
逢いたいのにな 会えないな
Even though I want to see you, I can't meet you.
嫉妬したい気持ち
The feeling of wanting to be jealous...
今日も頑張ってんだね どうか君に届くように
You worked hard again today, I hope it reaches you...
ああ 見守ってるずっと遠くから
Ah, I'm watching over you from far away, always...
ああ...
Ah...
ポリラタッタ スパリラダ...
Poriratatta sparilada...
たとえるならそれはドレスのように すっかり装いを替えて
If I were to compare it, like a dress, completely changing attire...
優しい光で輝きだす 夜の街
The night city begins to shine with a gentle light.
逃げないなら 暗闇は行こう 全部宙だと思えば
If you won't run away, let's go into the darkness, thinking of it all as suspended in air...
ずっと近くに見るよで不思議と怖くないよ
Strangely, seeing it so close, I'm not scared.
話すことは本当はいくつもあったけど
There were actually so many things I wanted to talk about, but...
言葉よりも想いがあふれ出して 響け よしんこに
My feelings overflowed more than words, echo into the seismograph...
感じ合ったメロディ 総言葉も常識もいらないでしょ
Melody we felt together, we don't need words or common sense, right?
君と歌えるのなら
If I can sing with you...
見渡せばほら この夜に浮かぶ
If you look around, see, floating in this night...
輝きのひとつひとつが 誰かを照らすという優しさで繋がってる
Each and every sparkle is connected by the kindness of illuminating someone.
この街は 終わらないダンスを踊ってて
This town is dancing an endless dance...
感情が同調してた 重なっていく
Emotions were in sync, piling on top of each other...
響け よしんこに 感じ合ったメロディ
Echo into the seismograph, melody we felt together...
そう 言葉も常識もいらないでしょ 君となら聞かせて その声 今夜
Yes, we don't need words or common sense, right? If it's with you, let me hear that voice tonight...
だけは一緒に…
Only together...
過ごしてのまに びっくりじゃなくても 君と歌えるのなら
Even if it's not a surprise spent together... If I can sing with you
何も見えない 空 呼んで
Calling out to a sky where nothing can be seen,
ひどい顔で蒔き散らせ
scattering them with a terrible face.
浅かな世界で笑って
Laughing in a shallow world,
誰も知らぬボクは
I, whom nobody knows,
必死にしても守れない約束
promises I can't keep no matter how hard I try,
君にわかったんで
you figured it out.
もしもばかりつぶやいてしまう
I end up muttering 'what ifs' all the time.
笑い疲れた 傷ついていたいな
Tired of laughing, I want to stay wounded.
それでも無駄な小さな優しさ止めてないよ
Even so, I haven't stopped my small, useless kindness.
忘れられないように 大人ぶって入った嘘が
The lie I told acting grown-up so I wouldn't forget
動き出して ボクを押した
started moving and pushed me.
涙さえも 許されなくて 眠れない
I can't even be forgiven for my tears, unable to sleep.
要らない心 重くかさばり動けない
My unnecessary heart weighs heavily, unable to move.
深くなる夜 ボクと待ち合わせをした
I arranged to meet myself in the deepening night.
上手に拭えない昨日を押しつけて また見ないふり
Forcing on yesterday I can't wipe away, pretending not to see.
こんなんでごめん 諦めてないから 辛くて 諦めてないから 貫く
Sorry for being like this, but I haven't given up, because it's painful and I haven't given up, I'll push through.
正しさも分からず手を引いて 誰も知らぬボクは
Pulling my hand without knowing right from wrong, I, whom nobody knows,
約束を隠す 特別じゃない ただ普通でよかった
hiding the promise—it wasn't special, just being ordinary was fine.
ほめてあげてたら 長く伸びた前髪も好きになれた
If I had praised myself, I might have grown to like my long bangs too.
笑い疲れた 傷ついていたいな
Tired of laughing, I want to stay wounded.
それでも無駄な小さな優しさ止めてないよ
Even so, I haven't stopped my small, useless kindness.
忘れられないように 大人ぶって入った嘘が苦しい
The lie I told acting grown-up so I wouldn't forget is painful.
夢寝たりだい 楽しそうでもいいな 甘えられたいいな
Wanting to sleep, it's fine even if it looks fun, wanting to be spoiled is fine.
なれない ここはを 日の中から 明日へと並べ
Unused to this, arranging from within the days toward tomorrow.
当たり前じゃない 朝が 動き出して
A morning that isn't taken for granted starts moving
ボクを押した 涙さえも 許されなくて眠れない
and pushed me—I can't even be forgiven for my tears, unable to sleep.
手に入れた紅茶
The black tea I got,
朝の光 おしゃべり代わりに浮かべて揺らす
floating and swaying in place of morning light and conversation.
今日の始まりは ちょっと特別 そんな気持ちになるんだ
Today's beginning feels a little special, making me feel that way.
温めたミルク
Warmed milk,
落とせば カップジュースみたいに広がる
if you drop it, it spreads like cup juice,
ミニチュアの秘密の世界旅行 なんてね 夕暮れ 飲み干して 午後を迎えに行こう
a miniature secret world tour, or so I say—drinking down the twilight, let's go greet the afternoon.
少し読み進めた本 古い花びら潮の代わりに挟んで
A book I read a little further, with an old petal tucked inside instead of salt,
きっと次に開いたら その香りで物語が変わってる
surely the next time I open it, the story will change with that scent.
オレンジが滲む 水面に来ないあの日の雨が
The rain of that day that didn't come to the orange-bleeding water's surface
作ってく自然の位置で じっくり巡ったら新しい季節かな
making a natural position, leisurely going around—is it a new season?
君と迎えに行く
Going to greet you...
どんな街に沈もう 自分の話だから
Whatever town we sink into, because it's my own story,
特別を集めて 大きな束にしたいんだ
I want to gather up special things into a big bundle.
一緒にね お休みの前には ほんとはもう少し先の
Together, before rest, honestly a little further ahead...
幾度ぎのスパイス 一ふり ここを温めて
A spice of how many times, warming this place up,
星空見上げれば どこまでも飛び立つ 無限大の秘密の宇宙旅行
looking up at the starry sky, flying anywhere we want on an infinite secret space trip.
なんてね 夢を見て 朝を迎に行こう
Or so I say—having a dream, let's go greet the morning.
少し読み進めた本 朝を迎に行こう
A book read a little further... let's go greet the morning.
息をしている だから生きている 何度もずっと言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
Breathing, therefore alive, I've devoted words to it again and again.
息をしている 予分に見えている 青が染み出す 私にとっての何か
Breathing, looking extra, the blue bleeding out—something important to me,
ことが独々している ここはいつも変わらずに
throbbing constantly, here always unchanging,
せかし続ける ボタン一つの命
a single life of a continuing button.
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの 消えてしまえそうなの わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
Will you remember me until the very end? It feels like I might disappear, understand me, please understand me.
いつかは卒業をするんでしょう
If we ever graduate from this world,
日常に戻ったら私たちは
Once we return to our everyday lives,
いなくなるの
We'll become free,
命のような夢を見てるよ
Watching a dream like life unfold.
またねバイバイ
See you later, bye-bye.
あっ 光った流れ星
Ah, a shooting star flashed,
願いそびれ もう一回を待った
I missed my wish, so I waited for another chance.
あっ という間に夜が明け
Ah, the night broke in no time,
もういいやこのまんま散歩しよう
It's okay, let's just go for a walk like this.
あっ 横切った野良猫
Ah, a stray cat crossed my path,
色は黒？でも可愛いから優勝
Is it black? But it's cute, so it wins.
パン屋さんが開くのは 7 時
The bakery opens at 7 o'clock,
あと 10 分何しようっかな
What should I do for the next 10 minutes?
遠回りもーしーもーし亀さんよ
Taking a detour, hey there, Mr. Turtle,
今だけは君になりたい
I want to be you just for now.
ぴょんって跳んだうさぎさん
A hopping rabbit—
ひょんなこと雹が降る豹に出会う
By a strange chance, it hails, and I meet a leopard.
理屈だってあってないようなもんでファンタジー浮かべ今日もニヒルに
Reasoning doesn't make sense, floating in fantasy and smiling cynically today too.
そこの街灯すらも意外と
Even the streetlight there, surprisingly,
僕がイヤフォン外したら歌い出す
Would start singing if I took off my earphones.
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
Only in winter can I see the warmth of voices—
春や夏や秋はどこへと消えてしまうのか
Where does it disappear in spring, summer, and fall?
きっとそこにある触れる揺らぐ気づいて気づいてって
Surely, it's there, touchable, swaying, notice, notice, it's...
まるで心の中みたい
Just like inside my heart.
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
Only in winter can I see the warmth of voices—
春や夏や秋は誰かに届いてるのかな
In spring, summer, and fall, is it reaching someone else?
だってここにない消える消える
Because it's not here, it disappears, vanishes.
暑さも寒さも全部「ちょうどいい」の前触れ
The heat, the cold, all of it is a prelude to "just right."
「わっ」
"Wow."
瞬間、風が吹いた
A moment, a breeze blew,
どこかの桶屋が儲かったのだろう
Somewhere, a bucket shop must have made a profit.
彼女が大事に認めた特大級のラブレター
A giant love letter that she cherished
空を舞って、伝って、僕が拾う
Floats, travels, and I pick it up.
そんな運命待ちを途中下車
Waiting for such a destined meeting, I get off midway,
僕は僕の呼吸を重ねる
I stack my breaths.
長い長い旅
A long, long journey,
ゆっくりと進んでこう
Let's proceed slowly.
何でも解決してくれる「時間」ってやつが相棒だから
Because "time," which solves everything, is my companion.
息を吸って
Take a breath,
長い長い旅
A long, long journey.
おなかへったそろそろ…
I'm hungry, soon...
焼きたてのパンの香りに思わず
The scent of freshly baked bread
亀もうさぎに乗る
Even a turtle would ride a rabbit.
街灯も瞬いて眠った
The streetlights twinkled and fell asleep,
入れ替わり目を覚ました
Waking up in turns.
鳥たちもしもしか思召し
Birds, hello, what do you wish for?
どきどきはきせきぼうし召し
Excitement is a miracle, put on a hat.
はじまりはじまりおーしかし
It's the beginning, the beginning, oh really,
It's the beginning, the beginning, oh really.
「おいしそう」
"Looks delicious."
愛が言葉を見失ってる
Love has lost its words,
空が涙を降らせていたんだ
The sky was letting fall its tears.
誰のために
For whose sake?
なんのために これが運命だと言うの
For what reason do you call this fate?
嘘が街を包み込んで
Lies envelop the town,
鳥かご別に見声を上げていた
A birdcage raised its voice in separation.
たった一つの存在を保つ この場所で君を待ってる
In this place maintaining its single existence, I am waiting for you.
世界はとても苦しそうでした 私に何ができるというの
The world looked so painful; what could I possibly do?
歌うことが正しいかなんて 今も答えは見つからないけど
I still haven't found the answer to whether singing is right,
大丈夫みんながいる 私はここにいるの
But it's okay, everyone is here, and I am right here.
長い何十回があって君と出会うから
Through dozens of long moments, I get to meet you,
夜が明けていく光が降り注ぎ
So night breaks and light pours down.
喜び悲しみを考え前を向く 君と生きてここでこの場所で それが私の世界が
Thinking of joy and sorrow, looking forward, living with you here in this place—that is my world!
その一秒一瞬が煌めく
Every single second sparkles brightly.
過去が虹を壊したとしても
Even if the past shattered the rainbow,
夢が街を暗くして
Dreams darkened the town,
夢が街を暗くしても
Even if dreams darkened the town...
僕の中の僕に聞いた
I asked the me within myself,
どうしたいの?
"What do I want to do?"
そばにいるよ
I'll be right by your side,
君に笑ってほしいんだ
I want to see you smile.
生まれた意味を探しているの
I'm searching for the reason I was born.
転んでもただ走り続けていく
Even if I stumble, I'll just keep running on.
今を生きて明日を投げた
Living in the present and casting away tomorrow,
心が叫びたがってる
my heart is crying out!
タイムマシンに乗ってさ 別の未来を選ぶことができたなら
If I could ride a time machine and choose a different future,
君のいない世界を想像する そんな世界は想像できない
imagining a world without you is impossible.
届いてるよね
You can hear me, right?
この描くこの歌が 何千何万回だってあって 君を選ぶから
No matter how many thousands of times I sing this song, I will choose you!
夜が滲んでいく 水平線の彼方へ
As the night bleeds into the horizon far away,
響く鼓動のことを 確かに感じた
I could truly feel the beating of my heart.
始めよう君との未来を 繋いだ手を離さないで
Let's start our future together, and never let go of our linked hands.
大きな声で名前を呼んで
Call my name out in a loud voice!
奇跡を駆け抜けて
Sprinting through miracles,
どこまでもいけるよ
we can go anywhere!
ここからもう一度 君と私で始めよう 無限の中に生まれた物語を
From here, once more, you and I will start the story born within infinity.
君とどこまでも この世界が悲しみに溢れたとしても 私は歌を歌い続けていく
With you, even if this world overflows with sorrow, I will keep on singing.
君と生きる
Living with you,
ここでこの場所で それが私の世界だ
right here in this place—that is my world!
その一瞬が煌めく
That single moment shines so brightly!
傷ついた涙を流す君が 幸せだと思える世界になりますように 願いを込め歌う
May the world become one where you can feel happy—I sing this with my wish.
私最強で最弱な私 弱気な心をスーツで隠して
I am the strongest yet weakest me, hiding my timid heart behind a suit,
世界はいつも負けない 強気でしたいさせてよ
the world is never defeated, so let me act strong!
今日も一日スマートにライト 人をすり抜け走るステーション
Today too, speeding smoothly past people at the station,
楽しく処理してステージから ビルの見下して拍手してるだけ
handling things happily, looking down at the buildings from the stage.
みんなが思っているような 私を演じたのはいつから
Ever since when did I play the role everyone expected me to be?
わかんなくなってぐちゃぐちゃになっても 信じていたい
Even if I lose track and everything becomes a mess, I want to keep believing.
私最強で最弱な私 弱気な心をスーツで隠して
I am the strongest yet weakest me, hiding my timid heart behind a suit,
鏡に映る私をじっと見つめる 最強サイジャックガード
Staring intently at myself in the mirror, the ultimate psych-jack guard.
毎晩飛び出るノマドりもどん底な 今日昨日辛くても 明日はきっと笑ってる
Every night leaping nomad life, even if yesterday was painful, tomorrow will smile!
信じて信じて 何度裏切られても 何度だって立ち上がれる 私は最高最弱だ
Believe, believe—no matter how many times betrayed, I can stand up. I am the greatest!
みんなが思っているような 私でいたいだけなの わかんなくなってボロボロになっても 立ち続けたい
I just want to be the me everyone expects. Even if I get battered, I want to stand.
私 最強で 最弱なんだ
I'm the strongest yet the weakest.
壊れ果てなく叫び ひとりひとりだて
Breaking down, my piercing cry rings alone.
愛情は捨てられない 弱きあたしでいさせてよ
I can't discard love, let me be my weak self.
私 最強で 最弱なんだ
I'm the strongest yet the weakest.
弱き心をスーツで隠して
Hiding my weak heart beneath a suit.
最愛 いつも負けない 強いあたしでいさせてよ
My dearest, I always stay undefeated, let me be strong.
壁に映るあたしが じっと見つめ返してくる
The reflection on the wall stares right back at me.
強く愛されたくて悩むの 少し疲れてる
I worry because I want to be loved deeply, I'm a bit tired.
最強 最弱だ
The strongest, the weakest.
みんな、小豆！
Everyone, AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートどっち選ぶー？
Microphone in hand, map in the other—which heart of yours will you choose?
はい、ということで、始まりました！あずきメジャーデビューライブ「カワイイのピリオド」昼の部！
Yes, and with that, it has begun! AZKi's Major Debut Live 'KAWAII NO PERIOD' Daytime Show!
みんな来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you everyone for coming!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
なんと、現時は4年7ヶ月ぶりです！
Amazingly, it's been 4 years and 7 months!
今日この日を一緒に迎えてくれて、本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for celebrating this day together with me!
いやもう泣きそうになって待って待って、もうすぐやばい、まだこんなじゅばんなのに、じゅばんなのに！
Oh, I'm about to cry, wait, wait, it's way too soon, I'm already like this!
はい、ということで、今日はですね、生バンドを迎えて、声と音とみんなの思い出でいっぱいのライブにしたいなと思ってます！
Yes, so today, we welcomed a live band, and I hope to make this a live full of voices, sounds, and everyone's memories!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
会場の皆も、そして配信で見ているそこも君も、ペンライトを持って一緒に盛り上がってください！
Everyone at the venue, and you watching the stream, please hold your penlights and get hyped together!
よろしく！すごーい！
Please look forward to it! Wow!
えー、ということで、今日のハッシュタグ、#AZKiワンマン横浜昼ってぜひね、盛り上げていただけると嬉しいです。
Um, with that, I'd be so happy if you could hype up today's hashtag #AZKiOneManYokohamaDaytime.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
ありがとうー！
え、そしてそして、先日リリースしました、みんなルートフォアは聞いてくれましたかー？
And also, everyone, have you listened to 'Route Effect' which we released the other day?
聞いた！聞いた！聞いてきてくれたー？
You listened to it? Thank you for listening!
はい、その曲も今日はやっていきたいと思いますので、ぜひぜひ最後まで、あとね、あとね、あのね、昼と夜でセトリ全然違うんだよー！
Yes, we'll be performing that song today too, so please stay until the end, and also... the setlist is completely different between daytime and nighttime!
ということで、セトリにも注目してぜひ見ていってください！え、そしてここで、無料配信は終わりまーす！
So please pay attention to the setlist and enjoy! And with that, the free stream ends here!
えーー！
Nooo!
YouTubeでチラ見せが今配信されているんですが、この先はぜひ配信チケットをゲットしてお楽しみください！
A sneak peek is currently streaming on YouTube, but please get a streaming ticket to enjoy the rest!
ということで、国内向けはスポンサーにて、海外向けはストリーミングプラスにてチケット好評発売中ですので、ぜひ最後まで見てほしいなと思います！よろしくお願いします！
Tickets are currently on sale via Sponsor for domestic viewers and Streaming+ for international viewers, so I hope you'll watch until the end! Thank you!
みんな、どう？ライブ、楽しい？楽しい？楽しい？みんながそう言ってくれると、あずきもとっても、とっても、とっても楽しいです！
Everyone, how is it? Is the live fun? Fun? Fun? When you say that, AZKi is so, so, so happy!
じゃあ、いっちゃいますか！次はルートフォアから！
Well then, shall we go? Next is from 'Route Effect'!
この曲です
This is the song.
パパ パパピヤ
Pa, pa, pa, piya...
起きた 手に入れた紅茶
Woke up and brewed some tea,
朝の光 お砂糖代わりに浮かべて揺らす
letting the morning light sway like sugar.
今日の始まりは ちょっと特別
Today's beginning feels a little special,
そんな気持ちになるんだ
putting me in just that mood.
温めたミルク
Warming up some milk...
落とせば カップ中に沈むみたいに広がる 道草の秘密
Pouring it in, it sinks into the cup like a secret detour.
冒頭無料はこちらで終了です。
This concludes the free preview portion.
本編続きをご視聴されたい方は、SPWNにてご購入お願いします。
To watch the rest of the main feature, please purchase it on SPWN.